BHONE AUNG KYAW

Full-stack Web Developer

bhoneak@outlook.com

github.com/Dev-BhoneAK

+959-424048958

SUMMARY

Collaborative, Energetic, and Highly motivated software engineer with over 7 years of experience and a broad skill set in web development. Willing to take a challenging, high-performance-oriented role in the field of Software Engineering and building complex business software from the ground up, high traffic websites, and web apps. Specialized myself in PHP, Laravel, Javascript, React, Nodejs, Express, MySQL, and MongoDB.

EXPERIENCE

Myanmar Media Linkage – Full-stack Developer / Senior Team Lead August 2018 – June 2022

- Designed and developed backend and Rest API for agriculture app, cooperated with the nation's largest telecom company, using Laravel and Voyager admin.
- Maintained and added new features on lotaya.mpt.com.mm, one of the largest web portals in Myanmar, using laravel 5.6 and angular 2.
- Promoted from Full-stack Developer to Senior Team Lead, leading a team of developers across different products.
- Collaborated with cloud engineer, migrating projects from the local data center to AWS cloud which can reduce the company's monthly cost.
- Spearheaded a video social platform, tay.com.mm, as a company's main product which becomes the central pillar of the company's revenues.
- Contributed transcoding and storing videos on AWS S3 process as a microservice that can be used by the company's products related to videos.
- Designed and architected a payment gateway system that can be used by the company's internal and external products.
- Communicated and collaborated with different teams of engineers, designers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis
- Architected, designed, tested, and documented admin dashboard and Rest APIs for Nation's first-ever Fantasy Football League using Node.js

Alpha Plus - Senior Web Developer

June 2017 – July 2018 (1 Year Contract)

- Architected, designed, and developed Inventory Management and Trade Tracking System from scratch for warehouses using pure PHP.
- Designed and developed two static websites for travel & tour agencies.

Novitee - Junior Web Developer / Backend Developer

January 2015 - April 2017

- Implemented Purchasing and Inventory Backend System from scratch which is part of F&B solution provider using Laravel 4
- Developed and Shipped Kitchen Display System with Laravel 4.2, node.js, and socket.io for real-time communication within devices.
- Designed and developed Hotel Management System with pure PHP
- Customized printing function for passport reader which is used in Hotel Management System with C#

SEA Net Technology - Frontend Web Developer / Junior Programmer February 2013 – December 2014

- Designed and developed frontend web pages for shwedagonpagoda.com which is the official website for Shwedagon Pagoda
- Implemented Maha Dhamma Pala e-Library with pure PHP
- Participated as a team member in developing the 2013 SEA GAMES
 Equestrian Marking System(Endurance) for judges using C#
- Maintained and Tested the data storing process of printing Seafarers' OCR machine-readable identity document by the Ministry of Transport

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science B.sc (Physics)

Institute/University : Bago University Year of completion : January 2013

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

Diploma in Software Engineering

Institute/University : Cambridge ICT Year of completion : November 2011

Nano Degree Program (React)

Institute/University : Udacity Year of completion : June 2022

SKILLS

Programming Languages : PHP, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript

Libraries and Frameworks : Laravel, jQuery, React, Gatsby, Node.js,

Express, Bootstrap, Material UI

Tools and Platforms: Git, Gulp, Webpack, Heroku, Firebase, AWS

Markup and Style Languages : HTML, XML, CSS, SCSS

Database : SQL - MySQL, MSSQL, NoSQL - MongoDB

API : REST(XML, JSON), GraphQL

To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this application is true, complete, and accurate.